

Mario van Rooij

Software Engineer

Pebruary 27, 1998

+31 (0)6 2898 2519

thitps://snoeprol.github.io/

@ mariovanrooij@hotmail.com

Dutch

Software Skills

Python React Java Docker SQL/Mongo FastAPI

Social Network -



Languages

Dutch

English

German



About me

As a graduate with an MSc in Computational Science and a BSc in Physics, I have a solid foundation in computational methods, mathematics, and software engineering. My career has focused on defense-related fields, demonstrating my strong problemsolving skills. I also bring solid software experience from various ventures, and I am highly experienced in .NET. I am passionate about contributing to defense and security innovations, combining my technical skills with an interest in national security.

Working Experience

May 2024 -Software engineer DroneNet

Now

Now

Worked on creating a simulation environment for simulated drones.

Create post flight analysis.

April 2023 -**Quantitative Risk Analist**

ABN-AMRO

Risk modelling for mortgages. Developing credit risk models. Implementing risk models on Databricks, using spark, databricks, ML-

flow.

Jan 2023 – December 2023

Software Engineer

Merwylan - Immobilienplanet

Creating C-sharp application to create brochures for real estate. Product users could upload information of a house and generate

an automatic report.

Oktober 2022 **Software Engineer** Avalor AI

- December 2022

Working on millitary drone applications. Writing tracking algorithms, apps to control drones, working with GIS systems.

Jan 2021 -**Software Engineer** MyWonderTales

July 2023

Creating generative AI application that creates books based on an

input story, including relevant images, including physical books.

December

Thesis Intern

TNO, Intelligent Imaging

2021 – August 2022 Worked on privacy concerns in federated learning and developed my own method, which was later published in an article. Worked with

deep learning, compute clusters.

Education

Exchanges

2019 – 2020 **Erasmus Exchange Semester** **Humboldt University of Berlin**

Followed computational physics course, in combination with solid

state physics course. Also learned German.

Study

Master Studies Computational Science 2020 - 2022(Cum Laude)

University of Amsterdam

Complex System Simulation, Numerical Algorithms, Agent-based Modelling, Evolutionary Computing, Large Scale Data Engineering, Stochastic Simulation, Scientific Computing, Advanced Numerical Methods in Many Body Physics, Machine Learning for Physics and Astronomy, Programming Multi-core and Many-core Systems, Un-

certainty Quantification

2017 - 2020 **Bachelor Studies Physics and Astronomy** University of Amsterdam

Calculus, Astrophysics, Condensed matter, Programming for Physics and Astronomy, Research practicum, Theoretical Solid

State Physics

Publications/ Other

Paper Link Secure Sparse Gradient Aggregation in Distributed Architectures

Mario van Rooij, Sabina van Rooij, Henri Bouma, Andy Pimentel

IoTSMS, 2022

Instagram Founded a Small Company for AI Children's Books

Link *MyWonderTales*

2023

App Link Created an App that Matches Music Taste to Events Using Spotify

Gatharoo

2023